Guide to the Benjamin and Muriel Goldring Papers and Photographs TAM.374
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Legal Practice and Legal Research, 1931-2001
  This series includes correspondence and research relating to cases Benjamin Goldring worked on and research notes, drafts and background material for published and unpublished articles. Several files document his work for the National Lawyers Guild, in particular his work on a document representing a dissenting view of the Guild's 1977 report on Israeli treatment of Palestinian prisoners.
  - Article: "Anti-Semitic Propaganda" (BG), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Article: "Blacklisting as Criminal Punishment" (BG), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Article: "Elliot Freemont-Smith's Understanding in His Review of Navasky's 'Naming Names'" (BG), 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Article: "The List: Designated with Death" (BG), undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Article: "New York Civil Liberties Union Proposal to Constitutional Convention to Replace Grand Jury" (BG), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Article: "Views from the Brink of Criminal Law History," Typescript and Handwritten notes (I) (BG), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Article: "Views from the Brink of Criminal Law History," Typescript and Handwritten notes (II) (BG), 1967 (Box 5a, Folder 1)
  - Article: "Views from the Brink of Criminal Law History," Typescript and Handwritten notes (III) (BG), 1967 (Box 5a, Folder 2)
  - Business Expenses, 1959, 1979, 1982 (Box 5a, Folder 3)
  - Cases: Bleier, Katherine, 1957-1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cases: Family, 1956, 1960-1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cases: General, undated, 1951-1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: Legal Issues, 1960-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: General, undated, 1939-1967 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General, 1970-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Re: U. S. v. Eugene Frank Robel, 1966-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: U. S. Congress, N. Y. State Legislature, 1958, 1970, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cross, Ephraim: Obituary, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - General Writing (BG), undated, 1931-1948 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Goebel, Julius, 1972-1980 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Licensing (BG), 1951, 1963, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Memo: Constitutional Invalidity of the Wood-Rankin Committee (BG), undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study In 'Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli-Occupied West Bank and Gaza: Report of the NLG 1977 Middle East Delegation' ," Correspondence (I) (BG), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study In 'Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli-Occupied West Bank and Gaza: Report of the NLG 1977 Middle East Delegation' ," Correspondence (II) (BG), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study...," incomplete (BG), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study...," Initial Draft and Notes (I) (BG), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study...," Initial Draft and Notes (II) (BG), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study...," Reprint and Correspondence (I) (BG), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study...," Reprint and Correspondence (II) (BG), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Analytic Study...," Reprint with Changes (BG), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - National Lawyers Guild; Criminal Justice Task Force, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Education for What? NLG and the Palestinian Question", "We Mastermind Imperialism's Destruction the West-Bank and Gaza-Strip Palestinians and the PLO" (BG), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - National Lawyers Guild: FBI Lawsuit, undated, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - National Lawyers Guild: General, 1960-1979 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - National Lawyers Guild: General, undated, 1980-1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - National Lawyers Guild: General, Anti-Semitism Task Force, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - National Lawyers Guild: General, International Committee, undated, 1979-1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - National Lawyers Guild: General, National Executive Board (NEB), undated, 1972-1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - National Lawyers Guild: General, New York City Chapter, undated, 1960-2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Israel and Amnesty International, 1976-1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Israel and Palestine Research, Correspondence (BG), 1976-1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Israel and Palestine Research, General (I), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Israel and Palestine Research, General (II), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Israel and Palestine Research, NLG Publications, undated, 1967, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Israel and The International Committee of the Red Cross, 1969-1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Minority Report of the Middle East Delegation of the NLG on Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli Occupied Territories," Ad Hoc Committee to Publish the Report, Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Minority Report of the Middle East Delegation of the NLG on Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli Occupied Territories," Howard Dickstein (Final), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Minority Report of the Middle East Delegation of the NLG on Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli Occupied Territories," Howard Dickstein (versions I and II), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "On Majority Mideast Report Re-Revised May 1978" (BG) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "On Revised Majority Mideast Report" (BG), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Report of the NLG 1977 Middle East Delegation Concerning Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli Occupied Territories" (drafts I-III), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - National Lawyers Guild: "Report of the NLG 1977 Middle East Delegation Concerning Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli Occupied Territories" (final revisions and National Executive Board response to Minority Report), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Response to Rev. L. Humphrey Walz "Lack of Integrity Not a Basis for Middle East Understanding" (BG), 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - National Lawyers Guild: Sami Esmail, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - National Lawyers Guild: United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization Meetings (UNESCO) on Israel and Palestine, 1974-1979 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - National Lawyers Guild: United Nations Report of the Special Committee to Investigate Israeli Practices Affecting Human Rights of the Population of the Occupied Territories, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - National Lawyers Guild: United Nations Report of the Special Committee to Investigate Israeli Practices Affecting Human Rights of the Population of the Occupied Territories, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - National Lawyers Guild: United Nations Report of the Special Committee to Investigate Israeli Practices Affecting Human Rights of the Population of the Occupied Territories, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Research: Alcatraz, Federal Prisons, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Research: Alcatraz, Federal Prisons, undated, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Research: Early British and European Law, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Research: Early British Law (I), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Research: Early British Law (II), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Research: Medieval British Law, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Research: Health Issues, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Research: Passport, Naturalization, Immigration Law, undated, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Research: Passport, Naturalization, Immigration Law (Browder and Bridges Cases), 1939-1941 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - U.S. v. William Schneiderman, Briefs, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - U.S. v. William Schneiderman, Correspondence and Research, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Rosenberg and Sobell Cases, 1951-2003
  This series contains administrative files and publicity materials produced by the National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case and the Committee to Free Morton Sobell, as well as other materials documenting the work of both organizations. Notable is Ben Goldring's correspondence with Morton Sobell's legal team, Murie Goldring's correspondence with Helen Sobell and with Aaron Katz (director of the National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case), copies of material on the Rosenberg trial released under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), and a draft of a book-length work by William A. Reuben on the Rosenberg case, with annotations by Ben Goldring.
  - "The Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, and Morton Sobell, Case: Sections of the Track," Typescript (BG), undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Legal Documents: U.S. Supreme Court, Rosenbergs v. U.S. (1951) and Sobell v. U.S. 1952, 1951, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - National Rosenberg-Sobell Committee: "A Request to the Judiciary Committee of the U. S. Senate to investigate the Conduct of the U. S. Attorney General's Office In the Rosenberg-Sobell Case", undated, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - National Rosenberg-Sobell Committee: General Files, undated, 1953-1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Ponsolle, Doris; Poem "Tribute To a Comrade-in-Arms", undated (Box 8, Folder 15a)
  - Research Notes on the Cases, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Rosenberg: "American Bar Association Subversive Rosenberg Activities Committee" (BG), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Rosenberg: American Bar Association Trial Re-creation: "Espionage Trial of the Century" (Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, NYC), Aug 9-10, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Rosenberg: Articles, Editorials, Reprints by the National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case, 1977-1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Rosenberg: Articles and Reprints, 1951-1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Rosenberg: Booklets, Programs, Pamphlets, undated, 1951-1969 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Rosenberg: Booklets, Programs, Pamphlets, undated, 1970-1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Rosenberg: Booklets, Programs, Pamphlets (non-English), 1953, 1983, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Rosenberg: Clippings (I), 1950's - c. 2000 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rosenberg: Clippings (II), 1950's - c.2000 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Rosenberg: Clippings (III), 1950's - c.2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Rosenberg: Cohn, Roy: Interview by William Kunstler; Interview by Jim Hartz, 1958, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 7A)
  - Rosenberg: Committee to Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case, General, 1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, Aaron Katz (includes writings by Katz), 1963, 1977-1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, BG, 1957-1974 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, BG, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, BG, 1976-1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, General, undated, 1959-1993 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, MG, 1952-1974 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, MG, undated, 1975-2003 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Rosenberg: Correspondence, Sarah Lichtenberg (concerning loss of job for supporting Rosenberg cause), undated, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Rosenberg: Edith Segal, Music and Poetry (autographed), 1955, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Rosenberg: Espionage, General, 1978, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Rosenberg: Flyers, 1952-1979 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Rosenberg: Flyers, 1980-1997, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Correspondence, BG, 1973-May 1976 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Correspondence, BG, Jun 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, "FBI Director Kelley Reveals that Chief Prosecutor Lied to Rosenbergs Jury," Typescript (BG), 1976 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Denial Codes and Inventory, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, General, undated, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Meeropol Suit, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Meeropol Suit, Copies of Exhibits, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Research Team Instructions, Internal Documents, and Correspondence, undated, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1961-1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Rosenberg: Freedom of Information Act, Released Files, 1971-1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Rosenberg: Funeral Service Card, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 11a)
  - Rosenberg: Greenglass, David, Copy of Affidavit on Rosenbergs, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Rosenberg: Judge Irving R. Kaufman, undated, 1974-1988 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Rosenberg: Judge Irving R. Kaufman "The Kaufman Papers," Pamphlet, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Rosenberg: Katz, Aaron, Exchange with MG over National Committee Procedures/Policies, 1988, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 14A)
  - Rosenberg: Legal Documents; Meeropols v. Louis Nizer (copyright claim), 1973 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rosenberg: Legal Documents; Rosenbergs Stay of Execution, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Rosenberg: Legal Documents; U.S. v. Irving R. Kaufman, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Rosenberg: National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case: General, 1976-1982 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Rosenberg: National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case: General, 1983-1989 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Rosenberg: National Committee to Reopen the Rosenberg Case: General, 1990-2001, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Rosenberg: National Committee: Internal Documents, Drafts, etc., 1973-1978 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Rosenberg: National Committee: Internal Documents, Drafts, etc., 1982-2005, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Rosenberg: Newsletters, 1975-1988 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Rosenberg: Reuben, William A., Unpublished Manuscript re: Rosenbergs (typescript with annotations BG) (I), [1970's] (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Rosenberg: Reuben, William A., Unpublished Manuscript re: Rosenbergs (typescript with annotations BG) (II), [1970's] (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Rosenberg: Reuben, William A., Unpublished Manuscript re: Rosenbergs (typescript with annotations BG) (III), [1970's] (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Rosenberg: Reuben, William A., Unpublished Manuscript re: Rosenbergs (BG notes and comments), [1970's] (Box 10A, Folder 1)
  - Rosenberg: Rosenberg Fund for Children, 1990-2003, undated (Box 10A, Folder 2)
  - Rosenberg: Scholarly Writing on the Case, undated, 1955, 1984 (Box 10A, Folder 3)
  - Rosenberg: Songs and Poetry, 1953-1954 (Box 10A, Folder 4)
  - Rosenberg: Student Papers on Rosenberg Case (2), 1997 (Box 10A, Folder 5)
  - Rosenberg: Theatrical Programs, 1969-1970 (Box 10A, Folder 6)
  - Rosenberg: "They Live," Burt Marnik (play and correspondence with MG), 1967 (Box 10A, Folder 7)
  - Rosenberg: Transcript of Public Statements, 1955-1993 (Box 10A, Folder 8)
  - Rosenberg: Venona Intercepts, General Information, Reports on Impact on Rosenberg History, 1994-1998 (Box 10A, Folder 9)
  - Rosenberg: Venona Intercepts, Morton Sobell's Comments, 1997 (Box 10A, Folder 10)
  - Rosenberg: Venona Intercepts (transcripts, redacted), 1995 (Box 10A, Folder 11)
  - Sobell: Articles, Clippings, 1956-2001 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Sobell: Articles, Clippings, Publicity Materials, undated, 1953-1968, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Sobell: Booklets, Programs, Pamphlets, undated, 1951-1969 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Sobell: Committee to Free Morton Sobell, Helen Sobell Materials, 1966-1969 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Sobell: Committee to Secure Justice for Morton Sobell: Internal Documents, Publicity Materials, etc., [early 1960s ?] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Sobell: Committee to Secure Justice for Morton Sobell: Publicity Material, undated, 1954-1965 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Sobell: Correspondence, BG, 1954-1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sobell: Correspondence, in Support of Sobell, 1954-1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Sobell: Correspondence, MG, undated, 1957-1997 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Sobell: Correspondence, MG, on Behalf of Mrs. Sobell and Committee, undated, 1957-1968 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Sobell: Correspondence, Sobell's Legal Team (with BG), 1956-1957, 1963, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Sobell: Helen Sobell, Poetry, Article, Obituary, 1956, 1959, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, Congressional Committees and Request for Executive Clemency, 1954, 1961, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, Sobell v. Attorney General and Director, United States Bureau of Prisons (District Court), 1968 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, Sobell v. U.S. (Supreme Court), 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, Sobell v. U.S. (Supreme Court), 1957 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, Sobell v. U.S. (Supreme Court), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, U.S. v. Sobell (Circuit Court of Appeals), undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, U.S. v. Sobell (District Court), 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, U.S. v. Sobell (District Court), 1966 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Sobell: Legal Documents, U.S. v. Sobell (District Court), 1967 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Sobell: Press Releases, undated, 1955-1968 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Sobell: Publications (not by the Sobell Committee), undated, 1952-1997 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Sobell: "The Rock," (play script author unknown ), undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Sobell: Transcripts of Public Statements, 1959-1964 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Series V: Political Reference Files, 1939-2003
  These files of clippings and printed matter cover a wide range of political groups, individuals, issues and events.
  - Affirmative Action, 1965-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the International Commission of Jurists, Inc., 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Broadcasting Corporation (ABC) Theater Rosenberg Trial Re-enactment, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Committee For Protection of Foreign Born, undated, 1951-1982 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - American Committee For Protection of Foreign Born: Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Amnesty for Vietnam Resisters, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Amnesty for Vietnam Resisters: Clippings, 1977-1979 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Anti-Semitism and USSR, 1975-1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Arts and Artists, undated, 1960-1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr., undated, 1968, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Belfrage, Cedric Local 1199 Hospital and Healthcare Workers Memorial Program, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Black Panthers, 1966-1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Brighton Beach, undated, 1988, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn, 1963-1989 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn: Clippings, 1976-1982 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Building in Brooklyn: Protests, Clippings, undated, 1983-1987 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Building in Brooklyn: Protests, Windsor Terrace, Brighton Beach Baths, etc., undated, 1984-1989 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Carter, Rubin "Hurricane", 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Carter, Rubin "Hurricane": Clippings, 1974-1977 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Cemeteries and Yizkor, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights, 1975-1981 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Chile, undated, 1973-1978 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Chile: Clippings, 1973-1979 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - China, 1966,1974 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Civil Liberties, American Civil Liberties Union, 1949-1988 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Civil Liberties: Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties, 1962-1980 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Civil Liberties: Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties: Clippings, 1961-1970 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Civil Liberties, Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1954-1966 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Civil Liberties, General and New York Civil Liberties Union, undated, 1949-1979 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Civil Liberties, Mieklejohn Civil Liberties Institute, 1976-2002 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Civil Liberties, National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1964-1997 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Civil Rights I, 1964-1994 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Civil Rights II, 1964-1994 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Civil Rights: Clippings, 1965-1984 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Communist Party, 1951-1984 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Communist Party: Clippings, 1965-1979 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Communist Fronts and the Subversive Activities Control Board, undated, 1963-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Communist Fronts and the Subversive Activities Control Board: Clippings, 1962-1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Covert Action Information Bulletin: Complete Index, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Criminal-Civil Law, undated, 1961-1966 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Criminal-Civil Law: Clippings, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Cuba, undated, 1961-1963 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Angela, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Death Penalty I, 1958-2000 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Death Penalty II, 1958-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Death Penalty: Clippings, 1967-1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Death Penalty: Mumia Abu-Jamal, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Education/ Public Schools, undated, 1964-1978 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - El Salvador, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Ellsberg-Russo Pentagon Papers, undated, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Ellsberg-Russo Pentagon Papers: Clippings, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Epton, William, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Epton, William: Clippings 1965-1968 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - FBI Negative Press, undated, 1974-1981 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - FBI Negative Press: Clippings, 1969-1980 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - FBI/CIA: Intelligence Gathering and Surveillance, 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - FBI/CIA: Intelligence Gathering and Surveillance: Clippings, 1968-1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Fifth Amendment, 1954-1969 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - First Amendment, undated, 1952-1969 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - First Amendment: Clippings, 1966-1976 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Frameups and Railroading, 1965-1980 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Frameups and Railroading: Clippings, 1976-1983 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1975-1982 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Freedom of Information Act: Clippings, 1975-1986 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Grand Jury, 1967-1981 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Grand Jury: Clippings, 1966-1982 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Guatemala, 1978-1983 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Guatemala: Clippings, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1951-1978 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Hiss, Alger: Clippings, 1962-1984 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Human Rights, undated, 1958-1978 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Immigrants/ Immigration, undated, 1971-1998 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Informers, 1962-1980 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - International Travel, undated, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - International Travel: Clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Investigative Committees: Clippings, 1950-1981 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Investigative Committees: Dalton Trumbo The Time of the Toad, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Investigative Committees: General, 1950-1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Investigative Committees: House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC), 1953-1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Irish Independence, 1971-1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)